Willow Alber-Martin

Boulder, CO · (720) 525-8664 · willow.albermartin@gmail.com · walbermartin.com

I am a driven undergraduate with extensive experience in instruction and communication. I am proficient at managerial tasks and event planning, with additional skills in lab settings and data science.

Education

Boulder, CO Jun. 2020 - Present University of Colorado, Boulder, Molecular and Cellular Biology

Bachelor of Arts, May 2022

GPA: 3.33/4.00

New York University, Shanghai, Biology Shanghai, China Aug. 2018 - Jan. 2020

Bachelor of Science, No degree conferred

GPA: 3.2/4.00

Experience

Engineers Without Borders San Fransciso Professional San Francisco, CA Apr. 2022 - Present

Chapter - Technology Coordinator

Update and manage, mailing lists, Google calendar, Boulder, CO Jan. 2022 - Present website, fundraising platforms, conferencing platforms, communications platform, and other chapter-wide Boulder, CO Jan. 2021 - Dec. 2021 technology uses

Manage login & password data to chapter online accounts

Collaborate with Marketing on website content

University of Colorado, Boulder - Learning Assistant Mentor

Coach new learning assistants in pedagogy techniques

- Promote application of classroom concepts to teaching diverse arrays of students
- Provide observational and auditory feedback to learning assistants on how they can improve their teaching

Facilitate weekly group mentoring sessions

University of Colorado, Boulder - Learning Assistant

- Respond to student concerns, teach co-seminars and hold office hours.
- Facilitate conversation between students in classroom and remote settings.
- Collaborate with faculty and other learning assistants to develop concise lesson material

Mentor Collective - Mentor

Boulder, CO Aug. 2021 - Present

- Engage one-on-one with freshmen to offer advice and suggestions on transitioning into a college
- Provide resources to students who are struggling and work with them to make academic plans.

Heart 2 Heart - Child Supervisor

Shanghai, China Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2019

Organized fundraisers for families with children in need of heart surgery, and spent time with pre and post-operational children while they were in the hospital.

Restaurateur Club - President

Shanghai, China Jan. 2021 - May. 2021

Communicated with restaurant owners in Shanghai to plan visits to their businesses for the student body chapter.

YouthRoots - Intern

Denver, CO Aug. 2016 - Dec. 2017

Created teaching modules for future classes and organized the annual end of year banquet.

Skills:

Lab Procedures/Assays:

- Conversational fluency in Mandarin
- Semi-conversational in Korean
- LaTeX, HTML/CSS
- R for data science/scripting

Restriction Digests SDS-PAGE Enrichment and Plaque assays

isolation **PCR**

- BLS Certified

Select Projects

- Developed a restriction enzyme simulator using Python and the *Saccharomyces* Genome Database for identifying cheap, off-the-shelf restriction enzymes that can be used for DNA fingerprinting.
- Built a low cost incubator for growing cultures.
- Compared DIY gelatin based cellular growth medium to lab grade agar.